# Xue TENG

York University, 4700 Keele St, Toronto, Canada

♦ +1(647)867-1253 

xueteng@yorku.ca ♦ Google Scholar ⊕ xuetengcode.github.io

## **Highlight & Research Interests**

As a multidisciplinary researcher, I have published in top-tier conferences/journals in all my research areas, including IEEE VR (top conference in Virtual Reality), the Journal of the American Chemical Society (JACS, Impact Factor 14.5), and the Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI, top-tier conference in AI). As of Sep 2024, my publications have 1561 citations based on Google Scholar.

#### Research interests:

- Shared Affordance and spatial consistency in Virtual, Augmented, and Mixed Reality
- Shared interaction and perception between virtual and augmented presences
- Inclusive VR: Fall risk assessment, instability prediction and user wellness across demographics

## **Degrees**

2019/9-2022/5, Department of Electrical Engineering & Computer Science, York University, Canada Master of Applied Science, Supervisor: Professor Robert Allison

Thesis Title: Depth perception under scaled motion parallax in Virtual Reality

- 2009/9-2014/6, School of Chemical & Biomedical Engineering, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore Ph.D. (Biomedical Engineering), Supervisors: Professor Huang Ling and Professor Song Hao
- 2005-2009, College of Chemistry, Nankai University, China Bachelor of Science

## **Employment**

2022/5 - Present, Department of Electrical Engineering & Computer Science, York University, Canada

Postdoctoral Visitor, Supervisor: Professor Robert Allison

Topic: Sharing in Mixed Reality

2015/9-2019/4, Data Scientist, Pulse Infoframe Inc., London, ON, Canada

## **Teaching Experience**

- 2024, LE/EECS 1015 Introduction to Computer Science and Programming, Course Director (100 registered students)
- 2023, GL/PSYC 3690 Perception, York University, Course Director
- 2023, CVR VISTA Vision Science Summer School, lab instructor & development (40 registered students)
- 2022, CVR VISTA Vision Science Summer School, group instructor

## **Services**

- 2024/02 Present, Vice Chair, IEEE Computer Society Toronto Chapter, Canada
- Upcoming 2024/11, Demo for Virtual Reality Open House 2.0 hosted by International Training Centre for Authorities and Leaders (CIFAL) York
- Upcoming 2024/11, VR demo following Visually Induced Motion Sensations
- 2023/12, Lab demo following Vision Research Conference hosted by Centre for Vision Research (CVR) and Vision:
   Science to Applications (VISTA)
- 2018, Reviewer: Annual Symposium AMIA

## **Presentations**

- 2024/04, Vision Science Society Poster presentation
- 2023/03, IEEE VR Oral presentation
- 2021/05, Vision Science Society Poster presentation
- 2015/10, Canadian Conference on Dementia Poster presentation

## **Publications**

Google Scholar: http://scholar.google.com.sg/citations?user=t8ch4nMAAAAJ&hl=en

#### **Conference Publications**

- [1]. **X. Teng**, L. Wilcox, and R. Allison, "Postural Responses After Gain Adaptation in VR," 8<sup>th</sup> International Conference on Visually Induced Motion Sensations, Toronto, Canada, 2024
- [2]. I. Gunasekera, X. Teng, F. Afolabi, R. Abadi, R. Allison, and L. Wilcox, "Perception of the Relative Size of Volumetric Shapes in Virtual Reality", 46th European Conference on Visual Perception, Aberdeen, Scotland, 2024
- [3]. **X. Teng**, L. Wilcox, and R. Allison, "Gain Adaptation in Virtual Reality," 24<sup>th</sup> Annual Meeting of the Vision Sciences Society (VSS), Florida, USA, 2024.
- [4]. **X. Teng**, R. Allison, and L. Wilcox, "Increasing Parallactic Change Compresses Depth and Perceived Distance", 23<sup>rd</sup> Scottish Vision Group (SVG), Dundee, Scotland, 2023
- [5]. **X. Teng**, R. Allison, and L. Wilcox, "Manipulation of Motion Parallax Gain Distorts Perceived Distance and Object Depth in Virtual Reality," 2023 IEEE Conference Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces (VR), Shanghai, China, 2023.
- [6]. **X. Teng**, R. Allison, and L. Wilcox, "Increasing motion parallax gain compresses space and 3D object shape", 23<sup>rd</sup> Annual Meeting of the Vision Sciences Society (VSS), 2023.
- [7]. **X. Teng**, L. M. Wilcox, and R. Allison, "Binocular cues to depth and distance enhance tolerance to visual and kinesthetic mismatch," 22<sup>nd</sup> Annual Meeting of the Vision Sciences Society (VSS), 2022.
- [8]. **X. Teng**, L. Wilcox, and R. Allison, "Interpretation of Depth from Scaled Motion Parallax in Virtual Reality," 21<sup>st</sup> Annual Meeting of the Vision Sciences Society (VSS), 2021.
- [9]. P. Dai, F. Gwadry-Sridhar, M. Bauer, M. Borrie, and X. Teng, "Healthy Cognitive Aging: A Hybrid Random Vector Functional-Link Model for the Analysis of Alzheimer's Disease," AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2017.

- [10]. **X. Teng**, P. Dai, F. Gwadry-Sridhar, and M. Borrie, "Clinical Feature vs Artificial Intelligence Feature: Risk Factor Analysis Based on Deep Learning," Alzheimer's Association International Conference (AAIC), 2016.
- [11]. P. Dai, F. Gwadry-Sridhar, M. Bauer, M. Borrie, and **X. Teng**, "Longitudinal Brain Structure Changes in Healthy/MCI Patients: A Deep Learning Approach for The Diagnosis and Prognosis of Alzheimer's Disease," Alzheimer's Association International Conference (AAIC), 2016.
- [12]. **X. Teng**, P. Dai, Objective Assessment of Risk Factors in Alzheimer's Disease (AD): a Novel Study Based on Artificial Neural Network, Canadian Conference on Dementia (CCD), 2015.

## **Journal Publications**

- [1]. Upcoming **Xue Teng**, Laurie M. Wilcox, Robert S. Allison, "Dissociation between perceptual and motor adaptation of motion gain distortion"
- [2]. F. Gwadry-Sridhar, H. McConkey, **X. Teng**, and D. S. Ernst, "The National Melanoma Research Registry: A Fundamental for Disease Characterization and Epidemiology," Annals of Oncology, vol. 29, p. viii460, Oct. 2018.
- [3]. J. Hou, J. Dong, H. Zhu, **X. Teng**, S. Ai, and M. Mang, "A Simple and Sensitive Fluorescent Sensor for Methyl Parathion based on l-tyrosine Methyl Ester Functionalized Carbon Dots," Biosensors and Bioelectronics, vol. 68, p. 20–26, 2015.
- [4]. W. Pei, B. Chen, L. Wang, J. Wu, X. Teng, R. Lau, L. Huang, W. Huang, "NaF-mediated Controlled-synthesis of Multicolor NaxScF<sub>3+x</sub>:Yb/Er Upconversion Nanocrystals," Nanoscale, vol. 7, no. 9, pp. 4048–4054, 2015.
- [5]. Y. Ding, **X. Teng**, H. Zhu, L. Wang, W. Pei, J. Zhu, L. Huang, W. Huang, "Orthorhombic KSc₂F<sub>7</sub>:Yb/Er nanorods: controlled synthesis and strong red Upconversion emission," Nanoscale, vol. 5, no. 23, p. 11928, 2013.
- [6]. P. Kannan, F. Rahim, **X. Teng**, R. Chen, H. Sun, L. Huang, D. Kim, "Enhanced Emission of NaYF<sub>4</sub>:Yb, Er/Tm Nanoparticles by Selective Growth of Au and Ag Nanoshells," RSC Advances, vol. 3, no. 21, p. 7718, 2013.
- [7]. **X. Teng** et al., "Lanthanide-Doped NaxScF<sub>3+x</sub> Nanocrystals: Crystal Structure Evolution and Multicolor Tuning," J. Am. Chem. Soc., vol. 134, no. 20, pp. 8340–8343, May 2012.
- [8]. W. Wei, T. He, **X. Teng**, S. Wu, L. Ma, H. Zhang, J. Ma, Y. Yang, H. Chen, Y. Han, H. Sun, L. Huang, "Nanocomposites of Graphene Oxide and Upconversion Rare-earth Nanocrystals with Superior Optical Limiting Performance," Small, vol. 8, no. 14, pp. 2271 2276, Apr. 2012.
- [9]. Y. Yang, Q. Shao, R. Deng, C. Wang, X. Teng, K. Cheng, Z. Cheng, L. Huang, Z. Liu, X. Liu, B. Xing, "In Vitro and In Vivo Uncaging and Bioluminescence Imaging by Using Photocaged Upconversion Nanoparticles," Angewandte Chemie International Edition, vol. 51, no. 13, pp. 3125–3129, Jan. 2012.

2024

## **Grants**

Title: Distortions in virtual environments

Funder: Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC)

Amount: 425,601

People: Laurie Wilcox (PI), Robert Allison (Co-PI), Xue Teng (Master's student)

Title: Nonlinear analysis of the effects of vision on postural stability

Funder: Vision: Science to Applications (VISTA)

People: Robert Allison (PI), Taylor Cleworth (Co-PI), Stephen Palmisano (Collaborative Partner), Jennifer Campos

(Collaborative Partner), Xue Teng (Master's student)

Title: Vision requirements for emerging stereoscopic display technologies in military aviation

Funder: Canadian Institute for Military and Veteran Health Research (CIMVHR)

Amount: 147,045

People: Laurie Wilcox (PI), Robert Allison (Co-PI), Xue Teng (Master's student)

Title: Sharing Mixed Realities

Funder: NSERC – Alliance & Qualcomm Inc.

Amount: 421,000

People: Robert Allison (PI), Laurie Wilcox (Co-PI), Xue Teng (Postdoctoral Fellow)

Title: Sensitivity to and consequences of mismatches between eye separation on and interocular distance

settings in VR

Funder: Meta Platforms Inc.

Amount: 247,000

People: Laurie Wilcox (PI), Robert Allison (Co-PI), Xue Teng (Postdoctoral Fellow)

## **Awards**

- 2021, Elsevier/Vision Research Virtual Travel Award
- 2019, VISTA Trainee Scholarship for Master's student
- 2009, Nanyang Technological University, PhD fellowship with full tuition fee waiver

## **References**

## Robert Allison, Ph.D.

Professor, York University Research Chair (YRC) Tier 2,

Center for Vision Research & Lassonde School of Computer Science and Engineering, York University

4700 Keele Street, Toronto, Ontario, Canada M3J 1P3

Phone: +1 416 736 2100 ext. 33265

Email: robert.allison@lassonde.yorku.ca

## Taylor Cleworth, Ph.D.,

Assistant Professor, School of Kinesiology & Health Science, York University

2275 Bayview Ave, North York, ON M4N 3M6

Phone: +1 416 736 2100 ext. 88116

Email: tclewort@yorku.ca

#### Scott MacKenzie, Ph.D.

Associate Professor, Lassonde School of Computer Science and Engineering, York University

4700 Keele Street, Toronto, Ontario, Canada M3J 1P3

Phone: +1 416 736 2100 ext. 40631

Email: mack@yorku.ca